{"prompt": "How many countries does Uber operate in?", "question": "How many countries does Uber operate in?", "answer": "Our technology is available in approximately 72 countries around the world, in cities across the United States, Canada, and in Latin America, Europe, and Asia"}
{"prompt": "What was the change in percent for gross bookings for Uber between 2020 and 2021?", "question": "What was the change in percent for gross bookings for Uber between 2020 and 2021?", "answer": "We had $10.9 billion in gross bookings for 2020 and $23.6 billion in gross bookings for 2021. This represents a 115% increase in gross bookings for 2021 compared to 2020."}
{"prompt": "What was the revenue for Uber in 2021?", "question": "What was the revenue for Uber in 2021?", "answer": "18,455 (in millions) or $18,455,000,000"}
{"prompt": "What was the gross bookings for Mobility rides in Q1 2020 at Uber?", "question": "What was the gross bookings for Mobility rides in Q1 2020 at Uber?", "answer": "4,565 (in millions) or $4,565,000,000"}
{"prompt": "What was the amount in Stock-based compensation expense for Year End 2021?", "question": "What was the amount in Stock-based compensation expense for Year End 2021?", "answer": "($566,566"}
{"prompt": "What comprises the Lyft transportation network?", "question": "What comprises the Lyft transportation network?", "answer": "Our transportation network is comprised of:\n• Ridesharing Marketplace: Our core offering since 2012 connects drivers with riders who need to get somewhere. The scale of our network enables us to predict demand and proactively incentivize drivers to be available for rides in the right place at the right time. This allows us to optimize earning opportunities for drivers and offer convenient rides for riders.\n• Express Drive: Our flexible car rentals program for drivers who want to drive using our platform but do not have access to a vehicle that meets our requirements. Through our Express Drive program, drivers can enter into short-term rental agreements for vehicles that may be used to provide ridesharing services on the Lyft Platform.\n• Lyft Rentals: In 2019, we launched Lyft Rentals to offer an attractive option for users who have long-distance trips, such as a weekend away. This is a separate consumer offering from Express Drive.\n• Lyft Autonomous: We have a strategic partnership with Motional (formerly Aptiv) to offer autonomous ridesharing services in Las Vegas and Los Angeles. Our partnership with Motional allows us to offer self-driving ridesharing services and further fuels the expansion of our network to more locations.\n• Lyft Public Transit: Available in select cities, our Transit offering integrates third-party public transit data into the Lyft App to offer users a robust view of transportation options around them and allows users to see transit routes to their destinations at no cost.”"}
{"prompt": "What is Lyft's growth strategy?", "question": "What is Lyft's growth strategy?", "answer": "Our Growth Strategy\nTransportation represents a massive market opportunity, one that we are in the very early stages of addressing. Our key growth strategies include our investments in:\n• Increasing Rider Use Cases. We are continuously working to make Lyft the transportation network of choice across an expanding range of use cases. We offer products to simplify travel decision-making, for example with our Lyft Pink subscription plan, Lyft Pass commuter programs, first-mile and last-mile services and university safe rides programs. We also provide centralized tools and enterprise transportation solutions, such as our Concierge offering, that enable organizations to manage the transportation needs of customers, employees and other constituents.\n• Expanding Our Network. We are proactively working to increase our network of available drivers and our network of drivers’ vehicles to make Lyft available to more people, in more places. We offer competitive incentives to drivers to encourage growth in our network. We have also been investing in our Lyft Driver Centers, Mobile Services and related partnerships that enable drivers to quickly get fixed prices for maintenance and related services for their vehicles. By making Lyft available in more markets and making it easy for drivers to get the high-quality vehicles they need to drive in our network, we can continue to make Lyft the preferred transportation network across even more of the United States and in growing cities around the world.\n• Building a Premium Express Transportation Service. In October 2019, we acquired Flexdrive, a flexible car ownership platform. In February 2020, we launched Flexdrive Express, a premium express car rental service that allows users to access high-end vehicles for ridesharing. This allows us to offer an even higher-end option that can address the needs of riders who are looking for a very high level of service, such as first-class business travelers or riders who want to enjoy a luxury vehicle for a special occasion.\n• Delivering the Best Possible Service. We are continuously working to deliver the best possible service to our riders. We have made significant investments in our matching technology that allows us to connect drivers with riders in real-time. We have also made investments in our customer service and operations to make sure we are ready to handle any issue that might arise. We offer a number of proprietary tools and services that enable us to proactively manage the quality of our service and reward drivers for providing high-quality services, such as our Driver Rewards program.\n• Increasing Our Share Price. We are committed to creating value to investors. A high stock price generally reflects a positive view"}
{"prompt": "Who is Lyft's main ridesharing competitors?", "question": "Who is Lyft's main ridesharing competitors?", "answer": "Uber"}
{"prompt": "Who is Lyft's main competitors in consumer vehicle rental market?", "question": "Who is Lyft's main competitors in consumer vehicle rental market?", "answer": "Enterprise, Hertz and Avis Budget Group"}
{"prompt": "What is the latest information on the workforce for Lyft?", "question": "What is the latest information on the workforce for Lyft?", "answer": "As of December 2021, Lyft's workforce consisted of approximately 4,453 employees in approximately 100 offices and additional locations totaling around 125,000 square feet of real estate available for employees"}
{"prompt": "When was Lyft incorporated?", "question": "When was Lyft incorporated?", "answer": "incorporated in 2007 as Bounder Web, Inc. and launched in 2012 as Lyft, Inc"}
{"prompt": "What operational risk factors does Lyft need to be concerned about?", "question": "What operational risk factors does Lyft need to be concerned about?", "answer": "Lyft needs to be concerned about the following operational risk factors:\n1. Competition: Lyft operates in a highly competitive ridesharing market in the United States and Canada. Increasing competitive pressure may cause bookings to decrease or prices to fall, which could adversely affect our revenue. Additionally, new competitors may enter the market, which could further decrease bookings and prices.\n2. Regulation: Our business is subject to the risks and uncertainties associated with existing and new laws and regulations applicable to our business, including but not limited\n3. Technology Risks: Our platform is built on a complex set of technologies that require significant investments in research and development to maintain their functionality and compatibility with increasing amounts of vehicle and rider data. Our ability to forecast rides and allocate drivers and vehicles in real-time is dependent on the accuracy and completeness of the data provided to us by our drivers and the vehicles’ GPS tracking systems. We are also subject to the risk that our investments in our proprietary technologies could be adversely affected by a decrease in the useful life of our assets or by the need to comply with new or modified laws and regulations regarding data privacy and security. Additionally, we are subject to the risk that third-party suppliers of our technologies do not maintain or update their offerings in a manner consistent with our requirements, which could disrupt our ability to provide a high-quality experience to our riders and drivers.\n4. Driver Availability and Retention: A significant portion of our current bookings come from ridesharing events in cities where there is a high demand for ridesharing services. If we are unable to replicate the success of our ridesharing events, we may be unable to attract new drivers to our platform. Additionally, driver availability and retention are critical to our ability to deliver a high-quality experience to our riders. If we experience issues with driver availability or retention, our ability to deliver a high-quality experience to our riders could be adversely affected.\n5. Marketplace Performance: Our platform is designed to optimize for the best possible marketplace performance, including the best possible matching of riders with drivers and the best possible pricing. However, our ability to optimize the marketplace is subject to various risks, including the risk that changes in the market or in the behavior of our key stakeholders could make it more difficult to achieve a optimal marketplace performance. Additionally, our ability to predict rider demand and driver availability is subject to various uncertainties, including the risk that our predictions are incorrect.\n6. Pricing: Our ability to set and maintain effective prices is critical to our ability to generate revenue. However, our ability to set and maintain"}
{"prompt": "Where does Lyft host their tech stack?", "question": "Where does Lyft host their tech stack?", "answer": "Our platform is built using a variety of technologies including AWS (Amazon Web Services) for our cloud infrastructure, Apache Kafka for message queuing, Apache Cassandra for our noSQL database, and a variety of open source tools such as React, React Native, Node.js, Python, SQL Server, and Git. Our consumer-facing app is available on the App Store and Google Play and is built using React Native. Our developer platform is built using a combination of React, Create React App, and a custom framework we have developed in-house. Our enterprise platform is built using a combination of React, Node.js, and SQL Server"}
{"prompt": "What are the estimated spending for cloud providers by Lyft?", "question": "What are the estimated spending for cloud providers by Lyft?", "answer": " Lyft estimates spending of approximately $1,580 per month for cloud services"}
{"prompt": "What available information is there about the cash flows for Lyft?", "question": "What available information is there about the cash flows for Lyft?", "answer": "2021\n2020\n(in thousands)\nNet cash used in operating activities\n(101,721)\nNet cash provided by (used in) investing activities   267,012\nNet cash provided by (used in) financing activities   (72,470)\nEffect of foreign exchange on cash, cash equivalents and restricted cash and cash equivalents (113)\nNet change in cash, cash equivalents and restricted cash and cash equivalents\n92,708\n$$\n$$\n(1,378,899)\n740,427\n$$\n$$\n(74)\nCash and cash equivalents as of December 31, 2021 were $740.4 million, which includes $92.7 million of unrecognized tax benefits. Revenue recognized as a result of contract liabilities being satisfied during the year was not material. Therefore, no revenue was recognized as part of the beginning or ending balance of accrued and other current liabilities as of December 31, 2021 or 2020"}
{"prompt": "What is the estimated useful life for Site Improvements as mentioned in the Uber 10-K?", "question": "What is the estimated useful life for Site Improvements as mentioned in the Uber 10-K?", "answer": "5-15 years"}
{"prompt": "What is the latest total dollar amount resulting from contract liabilities for Uber?", "question": "What is the latest total dollar amount resulting from contract liabilities for Uber?", "answer": "On December 31, 2021, we estimated that approximately $167 to $212 million of our revenue for the year ended December 31, 2021 and $157 to $203 million of our revenue for the year ended December 31, 2020 may be affected by contract liabilities related to payments made in connection with the lease for our Uber Open Platform in Miami, Florida, which was closed to new riders on July 20, 2020. In July 2020, we entered into an agreement to close the Uber Open Platform in Miami in order to comply with the requirements of the Florida Department of Health related to in-person medical services during the COVID-19 pandemic. Pursuant to the agreement, we agreed to pay certain providers a total of $20 million between July and October 2020 as part of the transition process. This amount was expensed as general and administrative expense for the year ended December 31, 2020 and 2021.  In July 2020, we also entered into agreements with providers in Miami to extend the terms of our existing agreements with those providers in order to allow for a smoother transition of customers to the closed Uber Open Platform in Miami. Pursuant to those agreements, we agreed to pay certain providers an aggregate of up to $22 million between July and October 2020 as part of the transition process. This amount was expensed as general and administrative expense for the year ended December 31, 2020. 50% of the $22 million was accrued and was recognized as expense for the year ended December 31, 2020, while the remaining 50% was accrued and was not recognized as expense at December 31, 2020 but will be recognized as expense through 2021. 50% of the $167 to $212 million estimated to be affected by contract liabilities related to the lease for the Uber Open Platform in Miami may be accrued and not recognized as expense until 2022 or later, while the remaining 50% will be recognized as expense in 2022 or later as applicable"}
{"prompt": "What was the total lease cost for 2021 for Uber?", "question": "What was the total lease cost for 2021 for Uber?", "answer": "2021 (in millions)   167\n2020 139\n2019 125\n2018 113\n2017 98\n2016 89\n2015 80\n2014 74\n2013 67\n2012 61\n2011 56\n2010 49\n2009 44\n2008 40\n2007 37\n2006 33\n2005 30\n2004 27\n2003 24\n2002 20\n2001 17\n2000 15\n1999 14\n1998 12\n1997 11\n1996 10\n1995 9\n1994 8\n1993 7\n1992 6\n1991 5\n1990 4\n1989 3\n1988 2\n1987 1"}
{"prompt": "What was the total long-term debt for 2020 at Uber?", "question": "What was the total long-term debt for 2020 at Uber?", "answer": "2020 was the first full year for Uber. 2020 was the first full year for Uber Luxury. 2020 was the first full year for our Platform and Rider Services and Mobility Services. 2021 was the first full year for our Commercial Drivers Services business. The following consolidated balance sheet information for 2020 and 2019 is in millions of U.S. dollars:\n2019\n--------------------------------\n     Cash and cash equivalents\n       166\n     Short-term debt\n       394\n     Amount due from Lyft for sold assets\n       103\n     Other current assets\n       157\n     Total current assets\n       820\n     Goodwill\n      139\n     Securities available for sale\n       566\n     Other long-term assets\n        72\n     Total long-term assets\n       977\n     Total liabilities\n       394\n     Stock-based compensation reserve\n       267\n     Other non-cash items\n        72\n     Total long-term liabilities\n        723\n     Fixed assets\n       125\n     Accumulated depreciation\n       (125)\n     Net fixed assets\n        0\n     Lease reserve for long-term lease liabilities\n       17\n     Long-term lease liabilities\n       167\n     Pension and other post-employment benefits\n      94\n     Other long-term liabilities\n       119\n     Total long-term liabilities\n       565\n     Stockholders’ equity\n      139\n     Less: Attributable to non-controlling interests\n        0\n     Stockholders’ equity as of December 31, 2021\n      1,652\n     Less: Attributable to non-controlling interests\n        0\n     Stockholders’ equity as of December 31, 2021\n       1,652\n     (in millions)\n     2020\n--------------------------------\n     Cash and cash equivalents\n       394\n     Short-term debt\n       394\n     Amount due from Lyft for sold assets\n       (103)\n     Other current assets\n       157\n     Total current assets\n       450\n     Goodwill\n      139\n     Securities available for sale\n       566\n     Other long-term assets\n        72\n     Total long-term assets\n       977\n     Total liabilities\n       394\n     Stock-based compensation reserve\n       267\n     Other non-cash items\n        72\n     Total long-term liabilities\n        723\n     Fixed assets\n       125\n     Accumulated depreciation\n       (125)\n     Net"}
{"prompt": "What were the changes in Unrecognized tax benefits at beginning of year for 2019 to 2021?", "question": "What were the changes in Unrecognized tax benefits at beginning of year for 2019 to 2021?", "answer": "2019 was $394 while 2021 was $867"}
